<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rTales: DataScience in Short</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on rTales: DataScience in Short</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>alvaroaguado3@gmail.com (Alvaro Aguado)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>alvaroaguado3@gmail.com (Alvaro Aguado)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2020 Alvaro Aguado</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcing Regression Coefficients in R - Part III Bayesian</title>
      <link>/forcing-regression-coefficients-in-r-part-iii-bayesian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>alvaroaguado3@gmail.com (Alvaro Aguado)</author>
      <guid>/forcing-regression-coefficients-in-r-part-iii-bayesian/</guid>
      <description>Question:I’m working on a regression model and I need to force the regression coefficients to be positive. How can I accomplish this in R?
Solution:For linear model regression model with restricted coefficients you have 3 options: Linear with nls, Bayes with brms and Lasso. Here we will look at Linear Model with bayes regresison with the brms package
In this case bayes provides a convenient way to restrict coefficients regularizing the coefficients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcing Regression Coefficients in R - Part II Lasso</title>
      <link>/forcing-regression-coefficients-in-r-part-ii-lasso/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>alvaroaguado3@gmail.com (Alvaro Aguado)</author>
      <guid>/forcing-regression-coefficients-in-r-part-ii-lasso/</guid>
      <description>Question:I’m working on a regression model and I need to force the regression coefficients to be positive. How can I accomplish this in R?
Solution:For linear model regression model with restricted coefficients you have 3 options: Linear with nls, Bayes with brms and Lasso. Here we will look at Linear Model with Lasso using glmnet
In this case glmnet provides a convenient way to restrict coefficients regularizing the coefficients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcing Regression Coefficients in R - Part I</title>
      <link>/restricted-coefficients-linear-regression-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>alvaroaguado3@gmail.com (Alvaro Aguado)</author>
      <guid>/restricted-coefficients-linear-regression-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Question:I’m working on a regression model and I need to force the regression coefficients to be positive. How can I accomplish this in R?
Solution:For linear model regression model with restricted coefficients you have 3 options: Linear with nls, Bayes with brms and Lasso. Here we will look at Linear Model with nls
The function lm does not provide a way to restrict coefficients. Instead we can use the function nls under the algorithm port.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here I will keep some resources like dynamic turorials done in R or Python</title>
      <link>/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>alvaroaguado3@gmail.com (Alvaro Aguado)</author>
      <guid>/resources/</guid>
      <description>Question: How do I calculate Type I, Type II and Power in a statistical hypothesis testing?Type I &amp;amp; Type II Error and Power</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>alvaroaguado3@gmail.com (Alvaro Aguado)</author>
      <guid>/news/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
When you click the Knit button a document will be generated that includes both content as well as the output of any embedded R code chunks within the document. You can embed an R code chunk like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is rTales? Who did this?</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>alvaroaguado3@gmail.com (Alvaro Aguado)</author>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>After some research about setting up a Blogdown site, conceptualization of ideas and also some inevitable procrastination, finally rTales has come to fruition.
What is rTales?rTales is (yet another) Data Science blog, but cutting the fluff. The idea is to answer practical data science questions first with a Reprex. This term stands for ‘Reproducible example’ and it was coined by Romain Francois.
New favorite word smash: reprex, for {rep}roducible {ex}ample.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>